# Chenghui Zhou

 $\verb|https://github.com/ZhouChenghui| \\ (+1) \ 412-500-3946$ 

chenghuz@cs.cmu.edu

# Profile

I am a PhD student researching artificial intelligence and machine learning. My current focus is on generative models – their theoretical foundations and applications in structured data generation, such as program synthesis, molecule generation, image captioning, text generation, and machine translation.

# **EDUCATION**

## Doctor of Philosophy, Candidate

August 2016 – December 2023 (Expected)

CARNEGIE MELLON UNIVERSITY

Machine Learning

Related Coursework: Deep Reinforcement Learning, Probabilistic Graphical Model, Intermediate Statistics,

Statistical Machine Learning, Convex Optimization

Advisor: Barnabás Póczos

Master of Science - Carnegie Mellon University

August 2016 – December 2018

MACHINE LEARNING

Advisor: Manuela Veloso, Barnabás Póczos

Bachelor of Science - McGill University

SEPTEMBER 2012 - MAY 2016

HONOURS COMPUTER SCIENCE & MINOR STATISTICS

Advisor: Joelle Pineau

# RESEARCH & WORK EXPERIENCE

## Applied Scientist Intern

May 2020 - August 2020

CodeGuru team, Amazon Web Service, Inc.

• Designed machine learning algorithms for effective search in code repositories.

# Research Intern Predictive Algorithm team, Zoll LifeVest

 $May\ 2018-August\ 2018$ 

• Designed machine learning algorithms to classify cardiac rhythms in ECG segments.

# Undergraduate Research Assistant

May 2014 - August 2015

Reasoning and Learning Lab, McGill University

- Developed algorithms to improve predictions for pedestrian tracking in robotics.
- Used method of moments and least squares to learn predictive linear Gaussian models.
- Evaluated algorithms on synthetic and real data of human walking trajectories.

## Publications & Working Papers

• Chenghui Zhou, Barnabás Póczos

Improving Molecule Properties Through 2-Stage VAE

Machine Learning for Structural Biology Workshop, NeurIPS, 2022.

• Chenghui Zhou\*, Frederic Koehler\*, Viraj Mehta\*, Andrej Risteski

Variational Autoencoders in the Presence of Low-Dimensional Data: Landscape and Implicit Bias

International Conference on Learning Representations (ICLR), 2022.

• Chenghui Zhou, Chun-Liang Li, Barnabás Póczos

Unsupervised Program Synthesis for Images by Sampling without Replacement Conference on Uncertainty in Artificial Inteligence (UAI), 2021.

- Chenghui Zhou, Chun-Liang Li, Barnabás Póczos Unsupervised Program Synthesis for Images Using Tree-Structured LSTM Deep Reinforcement Learning Workshop & Learning with Rich Experience Workshop (one of two selected oral presentations) NeurIPS, 2019.
- Robin Schmucker, Chenghui Zhou, Manuela Veloso Multimodal Movement Activity Recognition Using a Robot's Proprioceptive Sensors RoboCup Symposium, 2018.
- Chenghui Zhou, Manuela Veloso

Interception in Continuous Space Using Deep Reinforcement Learning Submitted to International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), 2018.

• Michiel de Jong, Kevin Zhang, Travers Rhodes, Aaron Roth, Robin Schmucker, Chenghui Zhou, Sofia Ferreira, João Cartucho, Manuela Veloso

Towards a Robust Interactive and Learning Social Robot

International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (AAMAS), 2018.

• Chenghui Zhou, Borja Balle, Joelle Pineau Learning Time Series Models for Pedestrian Motion Prediction

International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), 2016.

## Teaching

2021	Teaching assistant for	r Convex (	Optimization	(Carnegie Mellon	University)
------	------------------------	------------	--------------	------------------	-------------

- Teaching assistant for **Statistical Machine Learning** (Carnegie Mellon University)
- 2016 Teaching assistant for Introduction to Software Systems (McGill University)
- 2015 Teaching assistant for Foundations of Programming (McGill University)

## COMMUNITY SERVICE

2022	Served	l as a mentor in	the PhD	Peers	Program	of Machine	Learning	Department
2022	DCIVCU	i as a memor m		I CCI S	riogram	or macmin	Laming.	Depar union

2019 Served on the **Retreat Committee** of Machine Learning Department

2018 – 2020 Served as SCS4ALL Representative for Machine Learning Department

## Computer Skills

LANGUAGES

Languages Python, Java, C, Matlab, LATEX Chinese Native speaker Fluent

Operating systems Linux, Windows, OS X English

> PyTorch, Keras, JAX, Tensorflow, Sklearn Other French Basic

## Scholarships & Awards

2013 – 2016 Dean's Honours List – McGill University Fa	aculty of Science	ence
--	-------------------	------

- 2015Science Undergraduate Research Award - McGill University
- Emily Ross Crawford Scholarship McGill University 2015
- 2014 Scholarship for BSc Computer Science Honours Student – Le Réseau ACTION TI
- 2013 Faculty of Science Scholarship - McGill University
- 2012Descartes National Scholarship – Waterloo University (declined)
- 2012 **Hugh Brock Scholarship** – McGill University
- 2010 Gold Medal in Canadian Open Mathematics Challenge